One evening, a few days after the writing had appeared in Charlotte's Web,
the spider called a meeting of all the animals in the barn cellar. I shall
begin by calling the roll. Wilbur here, said the pig. Gander here, said the gender.
You sound like three ganders, muttered Charlotte. Why can't you just say here?
Why do you have to repeat everything?
It's my idio idiosyncrasy, replied the gender. Goose, said Charlotte. Here,
here, said the goose. Charlotte glared at her. Goslings 1 through 7.
Said the gozlings.
This is getting to be quite a meeting, said Charlotte. Anybody would think we
had three ganders, three geese, and 21 goings.
Sheep, answered the sheep all together. Lambs, answered the lambs all together.
Templeton, no answer. Templeton, no answer.
Well, we are all here except the rat, said Charlotte. I guess we can proceed
without him. Now, all of you must have noticed what's been going on around here
the last few days. The message I wrote in my web praising Wilbur has been
received. The Zuckermanmans have fallen for it, and so has everybody else.
Zuckerman thinks Wilbur is an unusual pig, and therefore he won't want to kill
him and eat him. I dare say my trick will work, and Wilbur's life can be saved. Hooray!
cried everybody.
Thank you very much, said Charlotte.
Now, I called this meeting in order to get suggestions. I need new ideas for
the web. People are already getting sick of reading the words some pig.
If anybody can think of another message or remark, I'll be glad to weave it into
the web. Any suggestions for a new slogan? How about pig supreme? asked one
of the lambs. No good, said Charlotte.
It sounds like a rich dessert. How about terrific, terrific, terrific, asked the
goose. Cut that down to one terrific, and it will do very nicely, said
Charlotte. I think terrific might impress Zuckerman.
But Charlotte, said Wilbur, I'm not terrific. That doesn't make a particle
of difference, replied Charlotte. Not a particle. People believe almost anything
they see in print. Does anybody here know how to spell terrific? I think,
said the gander. It's T E R I F I D C C.
What kind of an acrobat do you think I am? said Charlotte in disgust. I would
have to have St. Vitis's dance to weave a word like that into my web. Sorry,
sorry, sorry, said the gander. Then the oldest sheep spoke up. I agree that
there should be something new written in the web if Wilbur's life is to be saved.
And if Charlotte needs help in finding words, I think she can get it from our friend Templeton.
The rat visits the dump regularly and has access to old magazines. He can tear
out bits of advertisements and bring them up here to the barn cellar so that
Charlotte can have something to copy.
Good idea, said Charlotte. But I'm not sure Templeton will be willing to help.
You know how he is, always looking out for himself, never thinking of the other fellow.
I bet I can get him to help, said the old sheep. I'll appeal to his baser
instincts, of which he has plenty. Here he comes now. Everybody, keep quiet
while I put the matter up to him. The rat entered the barn the way he always
did, creeping along close to the wall.
"What's up?" he asked, seeing the animals assembled. "We're holding a
director's meeting," replied the old sheep.
Well, break it up, said Templeton. Means bore me. And the rat began to climb a
rope that hung against the wall. Look, said the old sheep. Next time you go to
the dump, Templeton, bring back a clipping from a magazine. Charlotte
needs new ideas so she can write messages in her web and save Wilbur's
life. Let him die, said the rat. I should worry.
You'll worry all right when next winter comes, said the sheep. You'll worry all
right on a zero morning next January when Wilbur is dead and nobody comes
down here with a nice pale of warm slops to pour into the trough. Wilbur's
leftover food is your chief source of supply, Templeton. You know that
Wilbur's food is your food. Therefore, Wilbur's destiny and your destiny are
closely linked. If Wilbur's killed and his trough stands empty day after day,
you'll grow so thin we can look right through your stomach and see objects on the other side.
Templeton's whiskers quivered. Maybe you're right," he said gruffly. "I'm
making a trip to the dump tomorrow afternoon. I'll bring back a magazine
clipping if I can find one." "Thanks," said Charlotte. "The meeting is now
adjourned. I have a busy evening ahead of me. I've got to tear my web apart and
write terrific."
Wilbur blushed. But I'm not terrific, Charlotte. I'm just about average for a
pig. You're terrific as far as I'm concerned, replied Charlotte sweetly.
And that's what counts. You're my best friend, and I think you're sensational.
Now, stop arguing and go get some sleep.